[ Intro - Red Warrior ]
《序曲 - 红衣武士》
"Once I had a dream and this is it"
“我曾有个梦 而这是……”
[ Dark Chest of Wonders ]
《神奇黑匣》
"Once there was a child's dream"
“曾经是一个属于孩子的梦想”
One night the clock struck twelve
钟声敲响了十二下 午夜降临
The window open wide
敞开窗户
"Once there was a child's heart"
“曾经有一颗童真的心”
The age I learned to fly
那时我幻想自己能飞翔
And took a step outside
飞出了窗外
"Once I knew all the tales"
“曾经我知道所有的童话”
It's time to turn back time
是时候让时间倒流了
Follow the pale moonlight
随着洁白的月光
"Once I wished For this night"
“曾经我渴望有这样一个夜晚”
Faith brought me here
信念带我来到这里
It's time to cut the rope and fly
是时候斩断绳索飞翔了
to a dream
飞向梦想
Far across the sea
穿越海洋
All the burdens gone
不再有任何负担
Open the chest once more
再一次打开匣子
Dark chest of wonders
满载奇迹的黑匣
Seen through the eyes
用双眼凝视
Of the one with pure heart
通过纯洁的心灵
Once so long ago
就像很久之前那样
The one in the big blue
那碧海中的宝物
is what the world stole from me
被上天从我手中偷去
This night will bring him back to me
今夜 它将回到我的手里
Fly to a dream
飞向梦想
Far across the sea
穿越海洋
All the burdens gone
不再有任何负担
Open the chest once more
再一次打开匣子
Dark chest of wonders
满载奇迹的黑匣
Seen through the eyes
用双眼凝视
Of the one with pure heart
通过纯洁的心灵
Once so long ago
就像很久之前那样
Fly to a dream
飞向梦想
Far across the sea
穿越海洋
All the burdens gone
不再有任何负担
Open the chest once more
再一次打开匣子
Dark chest of wonders
满载奇迹的黑匣
Seen through the eyes
用双眼凝视
Of the one with pure heart
通过纯洁的心灵
Once so long ago
就像很久之前那样
[ Planet Hell ]
《人间炼狱》
Denying the lying
谎言被掩盖
A million children fighting
孩子们自相残杀
For lives in strife
为了在争斗中生存
For hope beyond the horizon
为了那遥不可及的希望
A dead world
世界已经灭亡
A dark path
除了那黑暗之途
Not even crossroads to choose from
再无其它
All the bloodred carpets before me
殷红浸渍的大地在我面前
Behold this fair creation of god!
看呐 这公正的万物之神
My only wish to leave behind
我唯一的遗愿
All the days of the earth
就是让大地上的所有时日
An everyday
每一天
hell of my kingdom come
都成为我王国的地狱
The first rock thrown again
第一块石头又被掷出
Welcome to hell,little saint
地狱欢迎你 小圣徒
Mother Gaia in slaughter
大地女神在屠戮
Welcome to paradise,soldier
天堂欢迎你 士兵
My first cry never ending
我的第一声哭泣永不停止
All life is to fear for life
所有生灵都惧怕活着
You fool,you wanderer
你这个傻瓜 你这个徘徊者
You challenged the gods and lost
你质问上帝 终究只是徒劳
Save yourself a penny for the ferryman
留一枚便士给那地狱摆渡人吧
Save yourself and let them suffer
拯救自己 让别人去承受苦难吧
In hope
在希望中挣扎
In love
在爱中煎熬
This world ain't ready for the ark
这个世界还没准备好迎接方舟
Save yourself a penny for the ferryman
留一枚便士给那地狱摆渡人吧
Save yourself and let them suffer
拯救自己 让别人去承受苦难吧
In hope
在希望中挣扎
In love
在爱中煎熬
Mankind works in mysterious ways
未知的旅程还等着人们去探索
Welcome down
欢迎来到
To my planet hell
我的地狱
Save yourself a penny for the ferryman
留一枚便士给那地狱摆渡人吧
Save yourself and let them suffer
拯救自己 让别人去承受苦难吧
In hope
在希望中挣扎
In love
在爱中煎熬
This world ain't ready for the ark
这个世界还没准备好迎接方舟
Save yourself a penny for the ferryman
留一枚便士给那地狱摆渡人吧
Save yourself and let them suffer
拯救自己 让别人去承受苦难吧
In hope
在希望中挣扎
In love
在爱中煎熬
Mankind works in mysterious ways
未知的旅程还等着人们去探索
[ Ever Dream ]
《永远的梦》
Ever felt away with me
总感觉你已经离我而去
Just once that all I need
而我只想要一点共同的回忆
Entwined in finding you one day
总有一天我会不顾一切地去寻找你
Ever felt away without me
总感觉你是故意不告而别
My love,it lies so deep
我对你的爱 深藏心底
Ever dream of me
成为我永远的梦
Would you do it with me
你能否与我一起
Heal the scars and change the stars
让伤痕消逝 看星辰变换
Would you do it with me
你能否与我一起
Turn loose the heaven within
尽情放纵 如置身天堂
I'd take you away
我要带你远走高飞
Castaway on A lonely day
在寂寥中开始流浪
Bosom for A teary cheek
在你哭泣的时候依靠我的胸膛
My song can but borrow your grace
我的歌将因你更优美动听
Ever felt away with me
总感觉你已经离我而去
Just once that all I need
而我只想要一点共同的回忆
Entwined in finding you one day
总有一天我会不顾一切地去寻找你
Ever felt away without me
总感觉你是故意不告而别
My love,it lies so deep
我对你的爱 深藏心底
Ever dream of me
成为我永远的梦
Come out,come out,wherever you are
来吧 来吧 无论你身在何处
So lost In your sea
我已迷失在你海水般的眼眸里
Give in,give in for my touch
原谅我 原谅我的冒失
For my taste for my lust
原谅我的渴求和贪欲
Ever felt away with me
总感觉你已经离我而去
Just once that all I need
而我只想要一点共同的回忆
Entwined in finding you one day
总有一天我会不顾一切地去寻找你
Ever felt away without me
总感觉你是故意不告而别
My love,it lies so deep
我对你的爱 深藏心底
Ever dream of me
成为我永远的梦
Your beauty cascaded on me
你的美丽像瀑布一样倾泻于我
In this white night fantasy
在这白夜的狂想中
Ever felt away with me
总感觉你已经离我而去
Just once that all I need
而我只想要一点共同的回忆
Entwined in finding you one day
总有一天我会不顾一切地去寻找你
Ever felt away without me
总感觉你是故意不告而别
My love,it lies so deep
我对你的爱 深藏心底
Ever dream of me
成为我永远的梦
Ever felt away with me
总感觉你已经离我而去
Just once that all I need
而我只想要一点共同的回忆
Entwined in finding you one day
总有一天我会不顾一切地去寻找你
Ever felt away without me
总感觉你是故意不告而别
My love,it lies so deep
我对你的爱 深藏心底
Ever dream of me
成为我永远的梦
Ever felt away with me
总感觉你已经离我而去
Just once that all I need
而我只想要一点共同的回忆
Entwined in finding you one day
总有一天我会不顾一切地去寻找你
Ever felt away without me
总感觉你是故意不告而别
My love,it lies so deep
我对你的爱 深藏心底
Ever dream of me
成为我永远的梦
[ The Kinslayer ]
《弑亲者》
For whom the gun tolls
枪炮为谁而鸣
For whom the prey weeps
受害者在为谁悲泣
Bow before a war
在战争之前行屈膝礼
Call it religion
被称作了信仰
Some wounds never heal
有些伤口永不愈合
Some tears never will
有些泪水从不情愿
Dry for the unkind
因无情而干涸
Cry for mankind
对人类只剩下无泪哭喊
Even the dead cry
甚至死人也会哭嚎
Their only comfort
那是他们唯一的慰藉
Kill your friend,I don't care
杀死你的朋友 我不会介意
Orchid kids,blinded stare
死去已久的孩子 像盲人那样睁着
Need to understand
需要理解
No need to forgive
但不需要原谅
No truth,no sense left to be followed
没有真相 没有意义去留给人追寻
Facing this unbearable fear,
面对这无法忍受的恐惧
like meeting an old friend
就如同老友相遇
"Time to die,poor mates,
“去死吧 可怜的朋友”
You made me what I am!"
“是你造就了我现在的样子”
In this world of A million religions,
在这个有无数信仰的世界上
Everyone prays the same way
每个人都以同样的方式祈祷
"Your praying is in vain,
“你们的祈祷是徒劳的”
It'll all be over soon"
“很快一切都将结束”
Father help me,
上帝啊 拯我
Save me A place by your side!
让我到你身边
"There is no god"
“上帝并不存在”
"Our creed is but for ourselves"
“我们的信仰不过是为了自己”
"Not a hero,unless you die"
“除非你死了 否则你不会成为英雄”
"Our species eat the wounded ones"
“我们的种族蚕食着受伤的同类”
Drunk with the blood of your victims I do,
畅饮你祭品的鲜血吧
feel your pity-wanting pain
我真真地感受到你需要被怜悯的痛苦
Lust for fame,A deadly game
贪求名利是死亡的游戏
"Run away with your impeccable kin!"
“赶快逃离你那完美无缺的家族吧”
Good wombs hath borne bad sons
善良的母亲却孕育出了邪恶的后代
Cursing God,why?
这是诅咒吗 上帝 为什么
Falling for every lie
为每一句谎话堕落
Survivors' guilt
幸存者的罪孽
In us forevermore
在我们之间永存
15 candles
15根蜡烛映照着
Redeemers of this world
这世界的救世主
Dwell in hypocrisy:
浸淫在伪善中的人讲道：
How were we supposed to know?
我们又怎会知晓
[ The Phantom of The Opera ]
《歌剧魅影》
In sleep he sang to me
在睡梦中他为我歌唱
In dreams he came
在梦乡里他迎面而来
That voice which calls to me
那个呼唤我的声音
And speaks my name
喊着我的名字
And do I dream again
我是否又做梦了
For now I find
但现在我发现
The phantom of the opera is there
歌剧魅影就在那儿
Inside my mind
在我的脑海里
Sing once again with me
再次跟我一起歌唱
Our strange duet
我们奇异的二重唱
My power over you
我的力量支配着你
Grows stronger yet
愈发强大
And though you turn from me
纵然你转身离去
To glance behind
但只要你回眸一瞥
The phantom of the opera is there
歌剧魅影就在那儿
Inside your mind
在你的脑海里
Those who have seen your face
那些见过你面貌的人
Draw back in fear
都在恐惧中退却
I am the mask you wear
而我是你所戴的面具
but it's me they hear
但他们听见的是我
My/your spirit and your/my voice,
我的(你的)灵魂和你的(我的)声音
In one combined
融为一体
The phantom of the opera is there
歌剧魅影就在那儿
Inside your/my mind
在你的(我的)脑海里
Opera
歌剧
He's,the phantom of the opera
他就是 歌剧魅影
In all your fantasies
在你所有的幻想中
You always knew
你一直清楚的明白
That man and mystery
那个男人与那个神秘的迷
with both in you
其实就是你
And in this labyrinth,
在这迷宫里
Where night is blind
黑夜都被盲目了双眼
The phantom of the opera is there
歌剧魅影就在那儿
Inside your / my mind
在你的(我的)脑海里
Sing,my angel of music!!!
歌唱吧 我的音乐天使
Sing!!!
歌唱吧
My angel!!!
我的天使
Sing,sing,sing,my angel!!!
歌唱 歌唱 歌唱吧 我的天使
[ The Siren ]
《塞壬》
注：塞壬是希腊神话中半人半鸟的海妖
常用歌声诱惑路过的航海者而使航船触礁沉没
A lady with a violin,
一位女士用小提琴
playing to the seals
向水手们弹奏着
Harken to the sound of calling
倾听着那蛊惑之音
Who tied my hands to the wheel?
是谁把我的手绑在舵盘上了
The zodiac turns over me
我感觉天昏地暗
"Come to me"
“来我这里吧”
Somewhere there,my fate revealed
我的命运就在前方
I hear but how will I see?
我听到了但是怎么看不到
I tied myself to the wheel
我把我自己绑在了舵盘上了
The winds talk to my sails,not me
风儿吹着我的船帆 那个声音却渐渐消失
"Come to me"
“来我这里吧”
Somewhere there,my fate revealed
我的命运就在前方
I hear but how will I see?
我听到了但是怎么看不到？
[ Sleeping Sun ]
《沉睡的太阳》
The sun is sleeping quietly
太阳安静地沉睡着
Once upon a century
持续了一个世纪
Wistful oceans calm and red
沸腾的海洋变得平静而鲜红
Ardent caresses laid to rest
炽热的爱抚终于停歇
For my dreams I hold my life
为了梦想我尚且苟活
For wishes I behold my night
为了祈愿我遥望夜空
The truth at the end of time
真理存在于时间的尽头
Losing faith makes A crime
一旦遗失信仰便会衍生罪孽
I wish for this night-time
我希望这样的黑夜
To last for a lifetime
能伴随我整个人生
The darkness around me
黑暗包围着我
Shores of a solar sea
在这曾经的阳光海岸
Oh,how I wish to go down with the sun
啊 我多么想和太阳一起沉落
Sleeping
沉睡着
Weeping
哭泣着
With you
和你一起
Sorrow has a human heart
悲痛源自柔弱的心
From my god it will depart
我主必将使其远离
I'd sail before a thousand moons
我本应在无数个月圆夜前扬帆远行
Never finding where to go
却找不到属于我的方向
Two hundred twenty-two days of light
二百二十二天的光明
Will be desired by A night
将会被黑夜取代
A moment for the poet's play
这一刻可被诗人吟唱
Until there's nothing left to say
无论再多的语言都不足以描绘
I wish for this night-time
我希望这样的黑夜
To last for a lifetime
能伴随我整个人生
The darkness around me
黑暗包围着我
Shores of a solar sea
在这曾经的阳光海岸
Oh,how I wish to go down with the sun
啊 我多么想和太阳一起沉落
Sleeping
沉睡着
Weeping
哭泣着
With you
和你一起
I wish for this night-time
我希望这样的黑夜
To last for a lifetime
能伴随我整个人生
The darkness around me
黑暗包围着我
Shores of a solar sea
在这曾经的阳光海岸
Oh,how I wish to go down with the sun
啊 我多么想和太阳一起沉落
Sleeping
沉睡着
Weeping
哭泣着
With you
和你一起
[ High Hopes ]
《深深的希望》
Beyond the horizon
在那遥远的地平线
of the place we lived
我们曾生活的地方
when we were young
那时我们还是孩子
In a world of magnets and miracles
在这个充满诱惑和奇迹的世界
Our thoughts strayed constantly
我们的思想常常迷失
And without boundary
没有界线
The ringing of the division bell
离别的钟声
had begun
已然敲响
Along the long road
沿着那长长的路
and on down to the causeway
顺着堤道
Do they still meet there by the cut
他们还会在那交界处相遇吗
There was a ragged band that followed in our footsteps
我们走过的路像一条褴褛的带子
Running before time took our dreams away
快跑吧 在时间让我们老去之前
Leaving the myriad of small creatures that tried to tie us to the ground
离开那些不计其数 想把我们拖向大地的小生灵
To a life consumed by slow decay
生命被缓慢的腐烂吞噬了
The grass was greener
那时的草是那么的绿
The light was brighter
那时的光是那么的明亮
With friends surrounded
朋友们聚在一起
The nights of wonder
那美好的夜晚
Looking beyond the embers of bridges glowing behind us
遥望我们的身后 那桥已燃为灰烬
To a glimpse of how green it was on the other side
转身一瞥 看到另一边是那么的碧绿如新
Steps taken forwards but sleepwalking back again
虽不停地向前走 但还是像梦游一样原地徘徊
Dragged by the force of some inner tide
被一种内心的力量牵引着
At the highest altitude with flag unfurled
在那旌旗飘扬的高处
We reached the dizzy heights of that dreamed of world
我们达到了梦中那令人眩晕的高度
Encumbered forever by desire and ambition
永远被欲望和野心阻碍着
There's a hunger still unsatisfied
欲望永远得不到满足
Our weary eyes still stray to the horizon
我们疲惫的双眼仍然在看着地平线
Though down this road we've been so many times
尽管这条路我们已经走过多次
The grass was greener
那时的草是那么的绿
The light was brighter
那时的光是那么的明亮
With friends surrounded
朋友们聚在一起
The nights of wonder
那美好的夜晚
With friends surrounded
朋友们聚在一起
The dawn mist growing
晨雾正在蔓延
The water flowing
水正在流动
The endless river
在没有尽头的河流里
Forever and ever
直到永远
The grass was greener
那时的草是那么的绿
The light was brighter
那时的光是那么的明亮
The taste was sweeter
那时的感觉是那么的甜蜜
The nights of wonder
那美好的夜晚
With friends surrounded
朋友们聚在一起
The dawn mist growing
晨雾正在蔓延
The water flowing
水正在流动
The endless river
在没有尽头的河流里
Forever and ever
直到永远
[ Bless The Child ]
《愿上帝保佑这个孩子》
"I was born amidst the purple waterfalls"
“我生于紫色悬瀑中”
"I was weak,"
“身体虚弱”
"Yet not unblessed"
“但并没有受到诅咒”
"Dead to the world"
“我对这个世界没任何感觉”
"Alive for the journey"
“只为这段旅程而活着”
"One night I dreamt"
“一天晚上 我梦到”
"A white rose withering,"
“一朵正在枯萎的白玫瑰”
"A newborn drowning"
“一个婴儿”
"A lifetime loneliness"
“一生都沉浸在孤独中”
"I dreamt all my future"
“我梦到了我的未来”
"Relived my past"
“回想起我的过去”
"And witnessed the beauty"
“亲眼目睹了”
"of the beast"
“野兽的美丽”
Where have all the feelings gone?
那些感觉都去向了何处
Why has all the laughter ceased?
为什么所有的笑声都停止了
Why am I loved
为什么我在死去后
only when I'm gone?
才能得到爱
Gone back in time to bless the child
赶快回来保佑这孩子
How can I ever feel again?
我如何才能再有曾经的感觉
Given the chance would I return?
再给我次机会 我会回去吗
Why am I loved
为什么我在死去后
only when I'm gone?
才能得到爱
Gone back in time to bless the child
赶快回来保佑孩子
Think of me long enough
多想想我
to make a memory
足以生成回忆
Come bless the child one more time
再一次来保佑孩子
I've never felt so alone in my life
一生中我从未感到过如此孤独
As I drank from the cup
就如同我喝水时
which was counting my time
杯子在计量着我的生命
There's a poison drop
一滴毒液
in this cup of man
落在了人类的杯子里
To drink it is to follow
喝下它
the left hand path
意味着走左手边的路
Why am I loved
为什么我在死去后
only when I'm gone?
才能得到爱
Gone back in time to bless the child
赶快回来保佑孩子
Think of me long enough
多想想我
to make a memory
足以生成回忆
Come bless the child one more time
再一次来保佑孩子
Think of me long enough
多想想我
to make a memory
足以生成回忆
Come bless the child one more time
再一次来保佑孩子
"Where have all the feelings gone?"
“那些感觉都去向了何处”
"Why is the deadliest sin"
“为什么我爱你那样的爱”
"to love as I loved you?"
“会是最重的罪恶”
"Now unblessed,homesick in time,"
“现在 被诅咒着 被思念所缠绕着”
"Soon to be freed from care,"
“不久将了无牵挂”
"From human pain"
“不再遭受这人间的痛苦”
"My tale is the most bitter truth"
“我的故事便是那最悲惨的事实”
"Time pays us but"
“时间将会为我们偿还”
"with earth,dust,"
“但是 却只有泥沙和尘土”
"And A dark,silent grave"
“以及黑暗的、寂静的坟墓”
"Remember,my child:"
“记住 我的孩子”
"Without innocence"
“若不清白”
"The cross is only iron,"
“那十字架只是块铁”
"Hope is only an illusion"
“希望只是幻影”
"and ocean soul's"
“所谓海洋的灵魂”
"Nothing but a name"
“仅仅只是个名字”
"The child bless thee"
“那孩子将保佑你”
"and keep thee forever"
“守护你 到永远”
[ Wishmaster ]
《愿望之神》
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
Elbereth
星辰之后
Lorien
愿望之神
A dreamy-eyed child staring into night
一个有着梦幻般眼睛的孩子凝望夜空
On a journey to storyteller's mind
徜徉在故事讲述者的精神世界里
Whispers A wish speaks with the stars
对着星辰轻声许愿
The words are silent in him
在心里默默诉说
Distant sigh from A lonely heart
孤寂的心灵发出一声轻叹
I'll be with you soon,my shalafi
我即将来陪伴你 我的莎拉菲
Grey havens my destiny
灰港就是我的最终宿命
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
Silvara
西悠瓦拉
Starbreeze
星光
Sla-mori the one known only by him
只有他知道斯拉莫瑞
To august realms,the sorcery within
通往深藏魔法的威严领域
If you hear the call of arcane lore,
如果你听到神秘知识的召唤
Your world shall rest on earth no more
你将无法再踏足大地
A maiden elf calling with her cunning song
精灵少女用迷人的歌声呼唤
Meet me at the inn of last home
到最后归宿酒馆来见我
Heartborne will find the way!
哈特伯恩将知道怎样去
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
Wishmaster
愿望主宰者
Crusade for your will
为了你的意愿而发动圣战
A child,dreamfinder
一个寻梦的孩子
The apprentice becoming
即将成为学徒......
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
Master!
大师
Apprentice!
学徒
Heartborne,7th seeker
哈特伯恩 第七个追随者
Warrior!
战士
Disciple!
信徒
In me the wishmaster
我心中的愿望主宰者
[ Slayng The Dreamer ]
《杀死梦想家》
I'm a priest for the poorest sacrifice
我是神父最卑贱的祭品
I'm but a raft in a sea
我也是漂浮在
of sorrow,sorrow and greed
悲伤与贪婪之海的竹筏
You bathed in my wine
你沐浴在我的圣酒里
Drank from my cup,
喝光我杯中的酒
Mocked my rhyme
嘲笑我的诗韵
Your slit tongues licked
用撕裂的舌头
my aching wounds
舔舐我疼痛的伤口
Put a stake through my heart!
用木桩刺穿我的心脏
And drag me into sunlight
再把我拖入阳光下
So awake for your greed
你的贪欲如此清醒
As you're slaying the dreamer
你在杀死一个梦想家
Swansong for the wish of night
为夜的夙愿谱写最后一曲
God it hurts,give A name to the pain
上帝赐我痛苦之名
Our primrose path
我们通向地狱的快乐之路
to hell is growing weed
已经杂草丛生
Put a stake through my heart!
用木桩戳穿我的心脏
And drag me into sunlight
再把我拖入阳光下
So awake for your greed
你的贪欲如此清醒
As you're slaying the dreamer
你在杀死一个梦想家
Blame me,it's me
责备我吧 这就是我
Coward,A good for nothing scapegoat
一个懦夫 一个无用的替罪羊
Dumb kid,living a dream
一个愚笨的小孩 只能生活在梦想里
Romantic only on paper
浪漫的事只能写在于纸上
Tell me why
告诉我为什么
you took all that was mine!
你夺走的全都是我的
Stay as you lay don't lead me astray!
呆在那别动 不要将我引入歧途
Tell me why
告诉我为什么
you took all that was mine!
你夺走的全都是我的
Stay as you lay don't lead me astray!
呆在那别动 不要将我引入歧途
Wake up,mow the weed
醒来吧 割去那些杂草
You'd be nothing without me
离开我你什么都不是
Take my life if you have the heart
如果你有垂死的心
to die
那也带上我吧
You bastards tainted my tool
你们这些混蛋玷污了我的武器
Raped my words,played me a fool
戏弄着我的话语 愚弄我
Gather your precious glitter
收起你高傲的光辉
and leave me be
离开我吧
The great ones are all dead
真正的伟人都已死去了
And I'm tired,too
我也疲惫不堪
I truly hate you all!
我憎恨你们所有人
[ Kuolema Tekee Taiteilijan ]
《死亡造就艺术家》(芬兰语)
那一次 我看见了自己的梦
在星空下并没有察觉到它的渺小
那时 我倚着摇篮的围栏
像囚犯一样在那里写信
吾主 我写给你 让我变得如儿时所愿
你有万物之美 让死亡把我变成艺术家
我的天堂 我在这里创作
让我离去
让我离去吧
[ Nemo ]
《无名之人》
This is me for forever
这就是我
One of the lost ones
永远的迷途之人
The one without a name
没有名字
Without an honest heart as compass
没有一颗虔诚的心指引方向
This is me for forever
这就是我
One without a name
永远的无名之人
These lines the last endeavor
这几行字是我最后的挣扎
To find the missing lifeline
只为寻找失落的生命轨迹
Oh how I wish
哦 我多么渴望
For soothing rain
来一场慰藉的雨
All I wish is to dream again
我多期望能再次怀揣梦想
My loving heart
我火热的心
Lost in the dark
迷失在了黑暗中
For hope I'd give my everything
我愿付出所有来换回希望
A flower,withered between
一朵生命之花枯萎了
the pages 2 and 3
在生命的前几页
The once and forever
曾经和永远
bloom gone with my sins
与我的罪恶一起盛开并凋谢
Walk the dark path
走在黑暗的路上
Sleep with angels
与天使们共眠
Call the past for help
向过去呼唤求援
Touch me with your love
用你的爱抚摸我
And reveal to me my true name
揭示我与生俱来的真名
Oh how I wish
哦 我多么渴望
For soothing rain
来一场慰藉的雨
All I wish is to dream again
我多期望能再次怀揣梦想
My loving heart
我火热的心
Lost in the dark
迷失在了黑暗中
For hope I'd give my everything
我愿付出所有来换回希望
Oh how I wish
哦,我多么渴望
For soothing rain
来一场慰藉的雨
Oh how I wish to dream again
哦 我多么期望能再次怀揣梦想
Once and for all
过去的一切
And all for once
还有一切过去的
Nemo my name forevermore
无名便是我永远的名字
Nemo sailing home
无名的人 扬帆回家吧
Nemo letting go
无名的人 安心上路吧
Oh how I wish
哦 我多么渴望
For soothing rain
来一场慰藉的雨
All I wish is to dream again
我多期望能再次怀揣梦想
My loving heart
我火热的心
Lost in the dark
迷失在了黑暗中
For hope I'd give my everything
我愿付出所有来换回希望
Oh how I wish
哦 我多么渴望
For soothing rain
来一场慰藉的雨
Oh how I wish to dream again
哦 我多么期望能再次怀揣梦想
Once and for all
过去的一切
And all for once
还有一切过去的
Nemo my name forevermore
无名便是我永远的名字
My name forevermore
我永远的名字
[ Ghost Love Score ]
《幽爱之迹》
We used to swim
我们曾一同畅游在
the same moonlight waters
洒满月光的海域
Oceans away
那时
from the wakeful day
海洋尚在沉睡
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止”
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止”
Scent of the sea
大海的气息
before the waking of the world
在世界苏醒之前
Brings me to thee
把我领向你
Into the blue memory
领向那蓝色的记忆
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止”
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止”
Into the blue memory
进入那蓝色的记忆
A siren from the deep
大海深处的一个海妖
came to me
走向我
He sang my name my longing
他吟唱着我的名字和我的渴望
Still I write my songs
我依旧写我的歌
about that dream of mine
写关于我的那个梦
Worth everything I may ever be
付出我所有 都是值得的
The child will be born again
那孩子将再次降生
That siren carried him to me
那个海妖把他带向我这里
First of them true loves
他们的第一个真爱
Singing on the shoulders
在天使的肩膀上
of an angel
放声歌唱
Without care for love and loss
不用再担心爱和失去
Bring me home or leave me be
带我回家或弃我而去
My love in the dark heart of the night
我的爱陷入夜晚的黑暗深处
I have lost the path before me
我遗忘了前方的路
The one behind will lead me
后继者将指引我
Bring me home or leave me be
带我回家或弃我而去
My love in the dark heart of the night
我的爱陷入夜晚的黑暗深处
I have lost the path before me
我遗忘了前方的路
The one behind will lead me
后继者将指引我
"Take me"
“带走我”
"Cure me"
“拯救我”
"Kill me"
“杀死我”
"Bring me home"
“带我回家”
"Every way,every day"
“每一种方式 每一天”
"Just another loop in the hangman's noose"
“不过是在刽子手的绞索上再绕一圈”
Take me,cure me,kill me,bring me home
带走我 拯救我 杀死我 带我回家
Every way,every day
每一种方式 每一天
I keep on watching us sleep
我会看着我们入睡
Relive the old sin of adam and eve
重蹈亚当和夏娃古老的罪恶
Of you and me
你和我的罪恶
Forgive the adoring beast
饶恕这被崇拜的兽性吧
Redeem me into childhood
让我重回孩童时代
Show me myself without the shell
向自己展示自己最纯真的一面
Like the advent of may
就像五月到来
I'll be there when you say
当你诉说的时候，我会在那儿
Time to never hold our love
在那时 我们决不会相爱
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"So I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止”
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"So I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止”
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"So I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止”
"My fall will be for you"
“为了你我甘愿堕落”
"My love will be in you"
“我的爱将全部倾注给你”
"If you be the one to cut me"
“如果你是伤害我的那个人”
"So I'll bleed forever"
“我的血将永流不止……”
[ Stone People ]
《石人氏族》
[ Creek Mary's Blood ]
《克里克玛丽之血》
Soon I will be here no more
很快我将离开这里
You'll hear the tale
你将听到我的故事
Through my blood
从我的血迹那里
Through my people
从我的人民那里
And the eagle's cry
还有雄鹰的悲鸣那里
The bear within will never lay to rest
这其中的辛酸将永不消散
Wandering on horizon road
徘徊在地平线上
Following the trail of tears
追循着血泪之路
White man came
白人的到来
Saw the blessed land
觊觎着这片神佑的土地
We cared,you took
我们珍视 你们掳掠
You fought,we lost
你们征战 我们失去
Not the war but an unfair fight
这不是战争 而是一场不公平的掠夺
Sceneries painted beautiful in blood
美丽的景象在鲜血中绘出
Wandering on horizon road
徘徊在地平线上
Following the trail of tears
追循着血泪之路
Once we were here
曾经我们在这里
Where we have lived
自世界起源起
since the world began
我们便在这里
since time itself gave us this land
是时间赐予我们这块土地
Our souls
我们的灵魂
will join again the wild
将回归自然母亲的怀抱
Our home in peace and war and death
我们的家园经历了和平、战争、死亡
Wandering on horizon road
徘徊在地平线上
Following the trail of tears
追循着血泪之路
Once we were here
曾经我们在这里
Where we have lived
自世界起源起
since the world began
我们便在这里
Since time itself gave us this land
是时间赐予我们这块土地
Wandering on horizon road
徘徊在地平线上
Following the trail of tears
追循着血泪之路
Once we were here
曾经我们在这里
Where we have lived
自世界起源起
since the world began
我们便在这里
Since time itself gave us this land
是时间赐予我们这块土地
至今每到夜晚我仍会梦到那熟悉的狼群
奔跑的野马
一望无际的草原
永不停歇的风
掠过山巅
从未受到侵犯的族人边界
还有那属于伟大神灵的神圣土地
我至今仍深信
在每个夜晚
在每个白昼
我就像一只驯鹿
而你们就像狼群
使我更强壮
我们从未欠你们一丝一毫
我们唯一所欠的
是未能用生命报答我们的母亲
今天是个好日子
我要给母亲送上这支歌
我们的神灵来到此地
远远早于你们之前
甚至早于我们之前
并且将长久于此
直到看着你们的傲慢
将你们带向终点
[ Over The Hills and Far Away ]
《远山深处》
They came for him one winter's night
一个冬日的夜晚 他们为他而来
Arrested,he was bound
他被捕了 被绑了起来
They said there'd been A robbery,
他们说有一起抢劫事件
His pistol had been found
他的手枪已经被找到
They marched him to the station house,
他们把他押送到警察局
He waited for the dawn
他等待着黎明
And as they led him to the dock,
当他们带他去了被告席
He knew that he'd been wronged
他知道自己是被冤枉的
"You stand accused of robbery,"
“你被指控抢劫的罪名成立”
He heard the bailiff say
他听到执行官说
He knew without an alibi,
他知道无法辩解
Tomorrow's light
明天的阳光
would mourn his freedom
会悼念他的自由
Over the hills and far away,
越过群山 在遥远的地方
For ten long years
漫长的十年
he'll count the days
他将数着日子过
Over the mountains and the seas,
越过群山和海洋
A prisoner's life for him there'll be
囚犯的生涯开始了
He knew that it would cost him dear,
他知道这罪是如此之苛重
But yet he dare not say
但他不敢辩解
where he had been
在那关键证据的晚上
that fateful night,
他到底身在何处
A secret it must stay
那是一个不可告人的秘密
He had to fight back tears of rage
他强忍肆虐的眼泪
His heart beat like a drum
他的心跳如鼓
For with the wife of his best friend,
因为最后一个自由的夜晚
He spent his final night of freedom
他是和他最好朋友的妻子一起度过的
Over the hills and far away,
越过群山 在遥远的地方
He swears he will return one day
他发誓有一天会回来
Far from the mountains and the seas,
远离群山和海洋
Back in her arms he swear he'll be
他一定会重回她的臂湾
Over the hills and far away
越过群山 在遥远的地方
Over the hills and,
越过群山
Over the hills and far away
越过群山 在遥远的地方
Each night within his prison cell,
每个在囚牢的夜晚
He looks out through the bars
他透过铁窗向外眺望
He reads the letters that she wrote
他读着她写的信
One day he'll know
他知道总有一天
the taste of freedom
他会尝到自由的滋味
Over the hills and far away,
越过群山 在遥远的地方
She prays he will return one day
她祈祷他有一天能回来
As sure as the rivers reach the seas,
就像百川终归大海
Back in his arms he swears she'll be
她一定会重回他的臂湾
Over the hills and far away,
越过群山 在遥远的地方
He swears he will return one day
她坚信他有一天能回来
Over the mountains and the seas
越过群山和海洋
Back in her arms he swear he'll be
他一定会重回她的臂湾
Over the hills and far away,
越过群山 在遥远的地方
She prays he will return one day
她祈祷他有一天能回来
As sure as the rivers reach the sea,
就像百川终归大海
Back in his arms he swears she'll be
她一定会重回他的臂湾
Over the hills
越过群山
Over the hills and far away,
越过群山 在遥远的地方
Over the hills
越过群山
Over the hills and far away
越过群山 在遥远的地方
[ Wish I Had an Angel ]
《希望我有一个天使》
I wish I had an angel
我希望我有一个天使
For one moment of love
哪怕只能得到她片刻的爱
I wish I had your angel tonight
我希望我今晚就能拥有你的天使
Deep into a dying day
即使深陷末日
I took A step outside an innocent heart
我也要放弃我纯洁的心
Prepare to hate me,fall when I may
尽管憎恨我吧 我已然堕落
This night will hurt you like never before
今晚你将经受从未有过的痛苦
Old loves they die hard
长久的爱难以泯灭
Old lies they die harder
古老的谎言更难识破
I wish I had an angel
我希望我有一个天使
For one moment of love
哪怕只能得到她片刻的爱
I wish I had your angel,your
我希望我能拥有你的天使
virgin mary undone
你那未曾触碰的圣母玛利亚般的天使
I'm in love with my lust
我已爱上这贪婪的欲望
Burning angelwings to dust
将我天使之翼燃为灰烬
I wish I had your angel tonight
我希望我今晚就能拥有你的天使
I'm going down so frail and cruel
我正在坠落 那么虚弱和痛苦
Drunken disguise changes all the rules
酒醉的伪装改变了所有的规则
Old loves they die hard
长久的爱难以泯灭
Old lies they die harder
古老的谎言更难识破
I wish I had an angel
我希望我有一个天使
For one moment of love
哪怕只能得到她片刻的爱
I wish I had your angel your
我希望我能拥有你的天使
virgin mary undone
你那未曾触碰的圣母玛利亚般的天使
I'm in love with my lust
我已爱上这贪婪的欲望
Burning angelwings to dust
将我天使之翼燃为灰烬
I wish I had your angel tonight
我希望我今晚就能拥有你的天使
Greatest thrill not to kill!
最大的刺激不再是杀戮
But to have the prize of the night!
而是去获得黑夜的赏赐
Hypocrite!
伪君子
Wanna be friend!
也想要成为朋友
13th disciple who betrayed me for nothing!
第13个门徒就是那个无故背叛我的人
Last dance,first kiss,your touch,my bliss
最后的舞、我们的初吻、你的触摸、我的祝福
Beauty always comes with dark thoughts
美丽总伴随黑暗的思想
I wish I had an angel
我希望我有一个天使
For one moment of love
哪怕只能得到她片刻的爱
I wish I had your angel
我希望我能拥有你的天使
Your virgin mary undone
你那未曾触碰的圣母玛利亚般的天使
I'm in love with my lust
我已爱上这贪婪的欲望
Burning angelwings to dust
将我天使之翼燃为灰烬
I wish I had your angel tonight
我希望我今晚就能拥有你的天使
I wish I had an angel
我希望我有一个天使
I wish I had an angel!!!
我希望我能拥有一个天使